人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译：Iz  奈奈良  红豆包
校对：Iz          总监   IZ
时间轴：今        后期：吉吉
《开心汉堡店》
第三季第二十二集
你看上去太可爱了
You look adorable.
隆重的博物馆校外考察活动一切准备就绪
Ah, all ready for your big field trip to the museum.
你现在开心了
You happy now?
非常高兴  谢谢你自愿当志愿者
Very... thank you for volunteering to volunteer.
那我们扯平了吧
Yeah, so we're even.
我可是当了八年的志愿家长了
Well, I've been a parent volunteer for eight years,
而你是第一次参加这活动
and this is the first time you're doing it,
但没关系  好吧  我们扯平了
but, yeah, fine, we're even.
很好  要一直和福旺德那种人待在一起
Great... so, how did you survive eight years of being stuck
你这八年都是怎么熬过来的
with Mr. Frond?
带瓶酒去
Wine Thermos.
不如带瓶氰化物去[剧毒]
Get a cyanide Thermos
你到时候会想自杀的
since you're gonna want to kill yourself
因为校外考察实在是无聊至极
because field trips are dumb!
我同意  校外考察的确是无聊至极
I agree... field trips are dumb.
我记得我小时候有次去动物园考察
I remember being a kid, going to the zoo,
我和沃伦・菲茨杰拉德偷偷溜走了
and sneaking off with Warren Fitzgerald.
我们在斑马面前抽烟
We smoked cigarettes in front of the zebras.
假装抽烟
Half-smoked.
好吧  我没抽
I didn't really smoke.
把你的故事重新讲一遍  我刚到
Start your story over... I just got here.
你都不想看动物吗
Aw, you didn't care about seeing the animals?
那个动物园很烂
It was a pretty crappy zoo.
今天要去的博物馆也很烂
Yeah, it's a pretty crappy museum, too.
就这样我们还每年都去
And we go there every year.
-我喜欢那里  -我也是
- I like it. - Me, too.
我最喜欢的展览是"来自异域的沙"
The Sands from Exotic Lands exhibit is my favorite.
去年我回家后
Last year when I got home,
我屁眼里都是沙子
there was sand in my crack.
让我的屁屁亲自体验学习了一番
It was hands-on learning for my butt.
我想大家都有一个很棒的
I bet we all have a good
类似"来自异域的沙"的故事
Sands from Exotic Lands story.
我已经觉得无聊了
I'm already bored.
有时候无聊的事也能催生好事
Hey, sometimes good things come from boredom.
比如吉恩
Like Gene.
-多谢  -还有蒂娜
Thank you. And Tina.
击拳
Pow.
同学们  请按这个同伴随机分配表
Okay, people, take a look at my buddy board
去找你们各自的同伴
and find your randomly assigned buddy.
好吧  等等  等等
Okay, oh, uh, wait, wait.
看看  安迪和奥利被分在了一起
Oh, look, Andy and Ollie got assigned to each other.
多巧啊
What are the odds?
而我和
And I got...
我
Me.
我的搭档是瓶中精灵啊
I got a Genie in a bottle.
Genie[精灵]与Gene[吉恩]发音相似
要是我擦拭你  你会满足我的愿望吗
Hey, if I rub you, will you give me a wish?
-不会  -我听说能在这间博物馆
- No. - Hey, I heard you can see boobies
能看到来自世界各地的奶子
from all around the world in this museum
只要你知道往哪儿看
if you know where to look.
我们要去摸奶狂欢了
We're going on a booby bender.
奶子奶子奶奶奶
Boobity-boobity-a-la-la-la.
这我倒是能接受
This I could get used to.
鲁道夫・斯泰伯力兹
Rudolph Steiblitz?
等等  是中号鲁迪还是迷你鲁迪
Wait, is that Regular-Sized Rudy or Pocket-Sized Rudy?
中号鲁迪
Regular-Sized Rudy.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
有何高见
Hey, what's the big idea?
天呐  鲁迪  别偷偷跟着人家
Geez, Rudy, quit sneaking up on people.
戴个铃铛吧
Wear a bell.
天呐  我的搭档是亨利・哈伯
God, I have Henry Haber...
学校里的呆瓜
the school weirdo.
我去  我的搭档是蒂娜・贝尔彻
Great, I have Tina Belcher.
学校里最傻冒的女生
The dorkiest girl in the school.
不如这样
You know what?
我来教他怎么变得酷一点
Maybe I'll show him how to be cooler.
大家以前也认为我是个呆瓜
People used to think I was a weirdo, too.
不如这样  也许她只是需要有人
You know what? Maybe she just needs someone
教她怎么才能变酷
to show her how to be cool.
大家以前也认为我是个呆瓜
People used to say I was a dork, too.
一定很有意思
This'll be fun.
今天鲍勃去哪儿了
So, where's Bob today?
和孩子们去参加校外考察了
On a field trip with the kids.
在博物馆
At the museum.
我说他不去的话就对不起我
I guilted him into going.
-现在想他了吧  -其实
- You miss him, huh? - The thing is,
他还在这里
he's still here.
你没看到吗  他就是我
Don't you see? He's me.
是你  是那把刀
He's you, he's that spatula.
虽然这确实是间糟糕的餐馆
Sure, it's a crappy restaurant
是走过都不会注意到的那种
and people walk right by it, never take notice.
-等等  啥  -地板总是粘粘的
- Wait, what? - The floor's always sticky.
-粘粘的  -但这却是很多人的家
- Sticky? - But it's home for a lot of folks.
我都有点哽咽了
I'm getting choked up here.
好吧  现在的情况是
Okay... the thing is,
我让迫鲍勃去了
now that I made Bob go,
就感觉好像这些孩子们都不再需要我了
I feel like those kids don't need me anymore.
现在他成孩子们的大朋友了
Now he gets to play mama bird.
在公车里唱着歌
Singing the songs on the bus...
-琳达  -手拉手
- Linda. - Holding hands...
琳达  你还呆在这里干嘛
Linda, what are you doing here?
咋了
What?
去找他们  快去博物馆
Go to them! Go to the museum.
和你的孩子们在一起  去找他们
Be with your babies, go to them!
我得去  我得去
I got to go, I got to go!
-不用管我们  -我还在等
- We'll be fine. - I'm waiting on...
-我的薯条呢  -锁上门  琳达
- on fries. - Lock the door, Linda!
-出去  - 我们为什么要走
- Get out! - Why are we going?
-锁上门  -快走
- Lock the door. - Go!
千万别回头  千万别回头
Never look back, never look back!
你在画什么  亨利
What you drawing there, Henry?
我在为我下一部漫画小说设计机器人角色
I'm designing robot characters for my next graphic novel.
是这个系列的其中一部
It's part of a series.
有爱好很重要
It's important to have interests,
但也许你该找个不那么呆瓜的兴趣
but maybe you can find one a little less dorky?
这可酷了好吧
Uh, it's actually pretty cool.
只是你不懂而已
Maybe you just don't understand it?
我懂啊
Oh, I understand it.
一共有17部  你得一一按顺序读
There's 17 installments, and you really need to read them in order,
而你却没有  所以我很是怀疑
which you haven't, so I doubt it.
这会比我想象的要难
This is going to be harder than I thought.
机器人  倒是为我下一部色情同人小说
Robots? But that does give me an idea
提供了一个灵感  机器人屁股
for my next erotic fan fiction: Ro-butts.
那是什么声音
Hey, what's that noise?
大镲  随时都可能有人想即兴表演一段
My cymbals... you never know when somebody's gonna want to jam.
用那个给我造点势  好吗
Hmm, back me up with those, would you?
好吧  但是我没有
Well, okay, but I haven't...
福旺德老师
Hey, Mr. Frond.
小鸡为什么要横穿马路
Why did the chicken cross the road?
我不知道  露易丝  怎么了
I don't know, Louise, why?
那样他就会在不同的学区
So he would be in a different school district
而那里有不同的辅导员
where there's a different guidance counselor.
-赞同  -没错
- Hiya! - Yeah!
-露易丝  怎么了
- Louise. - What?
别那样说  别在这儿说
Don't say that here.
好吧  反正我也没词了
That's fine... I'm out of material.
那是老鼠展览吗
Ooh, is there a rat exhibit?
-他们应该是示威者  -示威者
- I think those are picketers. - Picketers?
连在里面能领到工资的人
Even the people who get paid to go in there
都不想进去
don't want to be in there!
这是有多可怕啊
That's how terrible it is!
你们的妈妈没来是件好事
It's a good thing your mom isn't here.
为什么  老妈喜欢抗议吗
Why, Mom likes protesting?
什么  不  她喜欢喊口号
What? No, she loves chanting.
谁不喜欢呢
Oh, who doesn't?
"神秘自然历史博物馆"去死吧
你好  我是玛德琳・格林伯格
Hi, Madeline Greenberg,
博物馆馆长
museum director.
我是菲利普・福旺德  孩子们的辅导员
Phillip Frond, counselor of children,
博物馆的朋友
friend of the museum.
我是鲍勃  我
I'm Bob, I, uh...
他就是个志愿者
He's merely a volunteer.
你们也许注意到了
Well, you may have noticed,
我们的UFMWD出了些问题
we're having a little trouble with the UFMWD?
我也有过类似的苦恼
I've had problems with that.
喝些红莓果汁吧[可预防尿道感染]
Drink some cranberry juice.
不  是博物馆工作人员和大学讲师工会
Hmm, no, it's the United Federation of Museum Workers and Docents.
-他们在罢工  -我继母也罢工
- They're on strike. - Oh, like how my stepmom's
除非老爸修好录像机  否则休想碰他
on a sex strike till my dad fixes the VCR.
没错  这不会有太大影响
Exactly, it hasn't affected much.
展览不变  乐趣也不变
We still have all the exhibits, all the fun,
只不过只有八分之一的员工
just one-eighth of the staff.
新开亚马逊展区  四层楼高
亚马逊展览
An Amazon exhibit?
也许今天也不会太无聊
Maybe this day won't suck so bad after all.
那还没开
Oh, that's not open.
啥  不是吧
What?! No!
罢工拖慢了我们的进度
The strike slowed us down there a little.
-好靓的蛇颈龙  -好靓的马啊
- Nice plesiosaur. - Nice horses.
-你说什么  -蛇颈龙
- What'd you say? - Plesiosaur.
最酷的恐龙
The coolest dinosaur.
亨利  喜欢的动物是好事
Hmm... Henry, it's great that you have a favorite animal,
但你就不能选酷一点的动物吗
but what about picking a cooler animal?
比如马  或小马
Like a horse or miniature horse?
这是你第一次做志愿家长  鲍勃
It's your first time as a parent volunteer, Bob.
琳达可是做得很好哦
Linda's set the bar pretty high.
我希望你能赶得上她
I hope you're up to it.
有这么棒的马甲
With great vest
你也该有更高的责任感
comes great responsibility.
好了  孩子们  和你们的同伴一起
Okay, kids, stick with your buddy
跟着大部队走
and stay with the group!
应该不会有人想成为迷失・马文
You don't want to be a Missing Marvin
或脱队・温迪吧
or a Walk-Away Wendy!
亚马逊展区  未开放
好吧  中号鲁迪  计划有变
Okay, Regular-Sized Rudy, change of plans.
我要去那里  你跟着我来
I'm going in there, and you're coming with me.
我觉得他们不会允许我们那么做
Yeah, I don't think we're allowed to do that...
是不会
Oh, we're not.
我们要去瓦格斯塔夫的学生
We're going where no Wagstaff student
从没去过的地方  亚马逊
has ever gone: the Amazon!
鲁迪  小点声
Rudy, just keep your voice down.
亚马逊
Amazon?
好的  亚马逊女士
Yes, ma'am-azon!
抱歉  好的  亚马逊女士
Sorry. Yes, ma'am-azon.
我很高兴你跟来了  鲁迪  我还以为
I'm glad you're up for this, Rudy. I thought I was gonna
我得单独行动了呢
have to get a buddy-ectomy.
开什么玩笑  这里太棒了
Are you kidding? This is great.
我从来没做过这样的事情
I've never done anything like this.
我妈很少让我参加校外考察
My mom barely let me go on this field trip.
好吧  我理解你这方面还是新手
Okay, I know you're new here,
但没有你这样秘密行动的
but this isn't how sneaking works.
-你得把包脱了  -好  没问题
- You have to ditch the backpack. - Yeah, sure.
不  我不是让你把它扔了
No! I didn't mean throw it.
好大声
That was loud.
好吧  你跟着我
Okay, I'll show you the ropes,
我们从绳子下钻过去
and then we're gonna go under the ropes
-摸遍所有的东西  -好的
- and touch all the stuff. - Yeah.
我要擤鼻涕
I need to blow my nose.
好吧
Uh, okay.
我得帮我拿着我才能擤
I can only blow it if you hold it.
-该我了  -天呐
- Now me. - Oh, my God.
鲍勃  该查点下人数了
Bob? Time for a head count.
四个  八个  十个
Four, eight, ten,
十四个  十六个
14, 16...
我现在要推开你了  奥利
I'm gonna push you now, Ollie.
我推了
I'm gonna push you away now.
我理解
I understand.
好吧  少了谁
Uh, uh, okay, who's missing?
天呐  露易丝  不出所料
Oh, man. Louise. Figures.
一切还好吧
A-are we good?
很好
Uh, uh-huh. Yeah.
相当好  只是我得过去一下
Definitely. I just got to go over here for a second.
马上就回
Be right back!
未开放
我早该知道她会进去
Of course she's in there.
露易丝  露易丝
Louise. Louise.
露易丝  快出来
Louise, come out of the plants.
谁是露易丝啊
Who's Louise?
我只是棵会说话的植物
I'm just a talking plant.
我的名字叫阔叶・绿蔷薇
My name is Leafy Greenbrier.
我是凯特・布什[也有灌木丛的意思]
And I am Kate Bush.
你们俩  听着
Listen, both of you.
我知道你们对博物馆没什么兴趣
I know you're not excited about this museum,
但我不能让你们
but I can't have you kids
变成迷失・马文
being Missing Marvins
和福旺德说的那什么蠢玩意儿来着
or whatever that stupid thing Frond said.
脱队・温迪
Walk-Away Wendys.
谢谢
Thank you.
你叫什么
Um, what's your name?
中号鲁迪
Regular-Sized Rudy.
Regular-Sized Rudy?
为什么要这样叫你
Why do they call you that?
-你看看我就知道了  -好吧
- Just look at me. - Um, okay.
你们两应该跟大部队一起行动
Listen, you two are supposed to stay with the group.
老爸  我一听你说"一起行动"
Dad, when I hear "Stay with the group,"
就偏想单独行动
I leave the group.
我知道  露易丝  你那样好讨人厌
Yeah, Louise, that can be annoying.
好吧  我们来时走的哪条路
All right, which way did we come in?
过来  走这边
Uh, come on, this way.
不要  你才该过来
No, you come on.
老爸  你看看四周  我们在雨林里呢
Dad, look around. We're in the jungle.
咱就不能逛一小小会儿吗
Can we just for a second walk around a little?
-确实挺震撼的  -就是啊
- Hmm. It is kind of impressive. - Yeah.
但我们都心知肚明  我得带你们回去
But we both know I have to take you guys back.
你让我想起我妈了
You remind me of my mom.
她也不喜欢好玩的东西
She hates fun, too.
快躲起来  蹲下
Hide. Get down.
喂  谁在那儿
Hey! Who's over there?
有人在那儿吗
Somebody over there?
都别出声
Everybody shut up.
有人吗
Hello?
拜托  杰夫  你明知我讨厌植物的
Come on, Jeff, you know I hate plants.
他们要是看到我肯定会大吃一惊的
Oh, they're gonna drop their juice boxes when they see me.
博物馆管理层处事不公  还反工会
Museum management is unfair and anti-union.
我听到了  大哥
Yeah, I hear that, buddy.
不不  我们在进行抗议
No, no, we're protesting.
我们的要求
What do we want?
公平
Fairness.
何时实现
When do we want it?
立刻马上
Now.
咋了  口号的问题吗
What? The chant?
是口号的问题  对吧
It's the chant, isn't it?
对  你们得大声吼出来
Yeah. You got to wow 'em.
像那什么...
Something like, uh...
工资薪水必须涨
Give us more money, damn it!
否则就把猛犸象剃光光
Or we'll shave the woolly mammoth!
休息时间要延长
Give us longer breaks for snacks
要不就把展品烧光光
or we'll burn the artifacts!
这你还真擅长
You're really good at this.
谢谢夸奖
Thank you.
好啦  祝你们好运  先走了
All right, good luck, got to go.
别呀  等等  我们需要你
No, wait. We need you.
千万记得  孩子们
Remember, kids,
想要动手摸的时候就用微笑代替
smiling is the new touching.
对极了
Nice.
还有  谁无视历史
Also, if you ignore history,
谁就注定要重蹈历史的覆辙
you're doomed to repeat it,
谁乱碰文物
and if you touch history,
谁就会被关六天禁闭
you will be suspended for six days.
没错  参观原始人展区的时候
Yes... and when you get to the pioneer exhibit,
要学习  不要调皮
learn but don't churn.
你究竟是何方神圣
Who are you?
你身体里住了位博物馆通吗
Is there a, uh... Mr. Museum?
没有
No, there is not.
好了  摸奶名单
Okay, booby checklist.
看看都有什么
Let's see what we got.
你在礼品店买的吗
Did you get that at the gift shop?
不是  我表哥的
Nope, it's my cousin's.
他列出了博物馆
He wrote down where to find
所有能摸奶的地方
all the boobs in the museum.
维京之奶  好棒
Viking boobies, yeah!
爱斯基摩之奶  等着我哦
Eskimo boobies, coming real soon.
这真是呆子[奶子]们的尴尬时刻啊
It's an embarrassment of boobies.
说得好  齐克
Good one, Zeke.
那是小吉米
That's Jimmy Jr.
你不认识他吧
You may not know him
他是学校有名的酷哥
because he's one of the cooler kids in school.
小吉米
Hi, Jimmy Jr.
蒂娜
Hi, Tina.
我认识他
I know Jimmy Jr.
你好  小吉米
Hey, Jimmy J.
你好  哈维
Hey, Harvey.
是亨利
Hen-Henry.
他总是开这种玩笑...
He's always joking like...
张冠李戴...
uh, not even my name, uh...
我想我们安全了
Okay, I think the coast is clear.
咱们还是归队吧
Let's get back to the group.
可才从保安眼皮底下逃过一劫啊
But we just hid from the guard.
在这多有意思啊
We're having fun here, ah?
我们去水上小屋看看  也不枉白来一趟
Come on, let's go into the stilt hut just so we can say we did it,
然后再照你说的  回到无聊的大部队
and then we can go back to the boring group
找无趣的福旺德老师
and that no-fun Frond
好好地过上无聊的一天
and have a crappy day just like you want.
行不行
Please.
还真的是水上的小屋呢
It's literally a hut on stilts.
好吧
Fine.
水上小屋  看完就走
Stilt hut and then that's it.
水上小屋
Stilt hut!
-水上小屋  -嘘
- Stilt hut! - Shh.
-水上小屋  -嘘  嘘
- Stilt hut! - Shh-shh-shush.
-鲁迪  真是个菜鸟  -我知道
- Rudy... rookie. - I know.
我们都来说悄悄话吧
Now we're all whispering.
这边总没有能摸的了吧  齐克
So nothing for you to check off here, Zeke.
他们奶子都有头发遮着
They all have hair covering their boobs.
整的跟个傻叉时尚杂志似的
Like a stupid fashion magazine, right?
别着急啊
But not so fast.
三  二
And three... two...
时间到
ta-ta time.
美中不足是没乳头
No nip, though.
你表哥真的很沉迷于此
Your cousin's really into this.
我还从没听过谁是恋奶癖呢
I never heard of anyone having a boob fetish.
这做得也太假了
Well, this isn't even remotely realistic.
我说  剑龙...
I mean, the stegosaurus...
亨利  我怎么说恐龙的来着
Henry. What did I say about dinosaurs?
你为什么要用这种口气说话
Why are you talking that way?
亨利  我只是想帮你  懂吗  兄弟
I'm just trying to help you, Henry, okay, buddy?
我才是想帮你呢  兄弟
And I'm just trying to help you, buddy.
我想说的是  剑龙  很明显
All I'm saying is, the stegosaurus... it's obviously...
-不不  亲爱的  -啥
- Uh-uh, honey. - Huh?
别这样
No.
真是呆瓜
What a dork.
-我知道  -我知道
- I know. - I know.
什么  你觉得我是呆瓜吗
Whoa, whoa. You think I'm the dork?
当然  大家都这么觉得
Of course. Everyone does.
不对不对  你才是傻瓜
No, no, no, no, you're the dork.
是吗  那只有一种方法了
Huh. Well, there's only one way to solve this.
方法可多着呢
Well, there's probably, like, a lot of different ways.
但是我们就先按你的呆瓜方法来吧
But why don't we try your dorky way?
好啊  因为这才不是什么呆瓜方法
Yeah, well, 'cause it's not the dorky way.
你能不摆出那副呆样  好好跟我说话吗
Can you just, it... drop the dork and just talk to me?
你现在看起来呆透了
You look so dorky right now.
再不涨工资
Make our paycheck more colossal!
化石成化屎
Or we'll poop on all the fossils!
好极了
Yes.
流氓
Rude.
很棒的水上小屋
Well, great stilt hut.
-没错  -棒极了
- Yeah. - The best.
好了  我们回去吧
Now, let's go back.
别  别  别呀
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
水上小屋是我的乐游雨林主意
The stilt hut was my fun jungle idea.
现在  轮到你出主意了
Now... what's, what-what's one from you?
你有什么主意
What do you got?
-回去  -说什么回去啊
- Um, go back. - Don't say "Go back."
沃伦・菲茨杰拉德是不会说回去这种话的
Warren Fitzgerald wouldn't say go back.
沃伦・菲茨杰拉德会说你变胆小鬼了
Warren Fitzgerald would say you've gone soft.
沃伦・菲茨杰拉德  我斑马故事里那人
Warren Fitzgerald? From my zebra story?
没错  来自那个有趣的鲍勃的过去
Yeah. From your fun past.
我有主意了  不过
I've got ideas, but...
你不说出来  我才不信呢
I don't believe you have ideas unless you say them out loud.
我有  我当然有  我随便四处看看
Yes, of course i have ideas. If I look around,
主意就跟泉涌一样的出来了
I could come up with something.
那好  你就四处看看  说个主意吧
Okay, well, then look around and come up with something.
好  那里  我们可以去那边
Okay, there. We're gonna go right there.
某人有长进了呢[要登高了呢]
Look who's stepping up.
但是  我们怎么上去呢
But, uh, how are we gonna get up there?
我们可以飞上去
We could fly.
好吧我们不能飞
I know we can't fly.
我们可以这样上去
We could just do this.
如何  说谁胆小鬼[软]呢  露易丝
Huh? Who's soft now, Louise?
你的胃  臀  还有大腿
Your stomach, your butt, and your thighs.
不过干得不错  走吧
But nice work. Let's go!
胆小鬼推来了一棵树
Mr. Softie just pushed over a tree.
我喜欢  赶紧的  中号
I like it. Hey, shake a leg, Reg Size.
我就来
I'll be right there.
我妈还说我不会爬树
And Mom said I'd never climb a tree.
好吧  看谁先到顶  来吧
All right, race you to the top. Let's do it!
先到的可以朝下面的人吐口水
First one up gets to spit down on the other.
放心  鲁迪  不会吐你的
Don't worry, Rudy, we're not gonna spit on you.
只要算上我就很开心了
As long as I'm included.
快看
Ooh, ooh. Look!
骆驼奶子
Camel boobies.
那是驼峰好不好
Those are humps.
奶子也是人的驼峰
One man's hump...
来自异域的沙
同学们  都集中过来
Okay, students, buddy up.
过几分钟
In a few moments
我们就要去博物馆的体验区了
we'll proceed to the hands-on room of the museum.
终于要去了
Oh, finally! Yay!
来自异域的沙
Sands from Exotic Lands!
沙  你开玩笑吧
Sand? Really?
就那东西赌了你家的马桶吗
That's what floats your scrote?
岂止是赌了马桶
And then some.
体验区哦[上手区]
Mmm, the hands-on room.
是唯一可以随便摸的地方
It's the one place you're allowed to touch.
你的皮肤都可以拿来展出了
Your skin should be its own exhibit.
你的头发都能送去亚洲假发工厂了
Well, your hair should be sent to an Asian wig factory.
-亨利・哈伯和我谁更呆  -你
- Who's a bigger dork, Henry Haber or me? - You.
-亨利  -白问了
- Henry. - Not helpful.
我和亨利谁更呆
Bigger dork, me or Henry?
-蒂娜  -亨利
- Tina. - Henry.
看来我们难分上下了
Well, looks like we're dork-locked.
我们要找不认识的人
We need fresh eyes.
你好  我是蒂娜  他是亨利
Hello, I'm Tina and this is Henry.
我是亨利
I'm Henry.
你觉得我俩谁更呆
Who do you think is the bigger dork?
我觉得你们俩不该玩这种游戏
Um, I don't think you kids should play this game.
给人贴标签会伤感情的
Labels lead to hurt feelings.
切  不该让呆瓜来评判呆瓜
Sheesh. Never ask a dork to judge a dork contest.
没错
Yeah.
快点  跟上啊  胆小鬼
Come on. Pick up the pace, softie.
胆小鬼  这话从一个直到八岁还叫我
Softie? That's funny coming from the girl
爹地的小女孩嘴里说出来真是滑稽
who called me Daddy until she was eight.
什么  怎么可能  你最好有个好律师
What? That's crazy. You better have a good lawyer,
因为我要告你诽谤  这位先生
'cause that is slander, sir.
我这是在笑
That's me laughing.
是时候来点升级版的了
Time to kick it up a notch, okay?
扭胯  抖臀
Shake your hips! Wiggle your butt!
裤子脱下来  再穿回去
Drop your pants and pick 'em back up!
-不  我不想脱裤子  -为什么
- No. I don't want to drop my pants. - Why?
我们成功了
We did it!
我真的打算吐口水了
You know what? I am gonna spit.
我们脱队是对的
Hey, I'm glad we ditched.
-很有意思  -我也这么觉得
- That was fun. - Me, too.
我们可以什么时候再来一次
Let's do it again sometime.
例如  等你七老八十的时候
Like, maybe when you're old and senile,
我就关了餐馆
I'll close the restaurant and come spring you
-带你逃出养老院  -啥
- from the nursing home. - What?
抱歉  跟我没关系
Sorry, I didn't want to do it,
是吉恩和蒂娜把你送进养老院的
but Gene and Tina put you in a nursing home.
还是条件不怎么好的那种
And not one of the nice ones either.
不是这个  你说你会经营餐馆
No, you said you'd be running the restaurant.
不  我只是说
Oh, no, I was just saying...
你会接手我们家的生意吗
You're taking over the family business?
对啊  怎样
Yeah, right.
-承认吧  你视我为榜样  -才没有
- Admit it, you look up to me. - No!
你现在把这大好的一天都毁了
S... You are ruining our perfect day right now!
我的天呐  我是你的偶像吗
Oh, my God, am I your hero?
恶心死了
Sick!
我高兴得肺都疼了
Fun... hurts... my lungs.
我还以为缺乏锻炼的是我呢
Wow. I thought I was out of shape.
搞什么...
What the...
这从哪儿冒出来的
This doesn't go here.
真是不听话的树
Disgusting tree.
这下要下去可难了
Whoa. That's gonna make getting down a lot harder.
靠  靠  靠
Oh, crap, crap, crap.
我们被困在上面了
We're stuck up here.
这一切都是个错误
This was a stupid idea.
鲁迪  你还好吧
Um, Rudy, are you okay?
我还没试过这么长时间不用吸入器
Haven't gone this long without my inhaler.
-吸入器  -我每隔两个小时要吸一次
- Inhaler? - I'm supposed to use it every two hours
不然就可能丢掉小命
or I could die.
-啥  -但我已经受够那东西了
- What? - But I'm sick of that thing.
好  好吧  你的吸入器在哪儿
O-okay. Where's your inhaler?
在  我的  背包里
In... my... backpack.
-你的背包呢  -我让他扔了
- Where's your backpack? - Um, I made him ditch it.
-什么  -不过别担心我
- What? - But don't worry about me.
我很享受当前的每分每秒
I'm loving every minute of this.
天呐  等等
Oh, my God. Wait!
保安  快回来
Security guy! Come back!
救命啊  救命
Help! Help!
你怎么不告诉我你要用吸入器呢
Why didn't you tell me you need your inhaler?
我是你兄弟啊  我们应该无话不说的
I'm your buddy. We're supposed to talk.
-无话不说啊  -这就是为什么你不能
- We talk. - This is why you can't just do
随心所欲的原因  露易丝
whatever you want, Louise,
凡事皆有因果
there are consequences.
你不该脱离组织
You shouldn't have left the group.
我也不该被你忽悠  做出这些事
And I shouldn't have let you talk me into doing this!
所以都是你的错咯
So it's your fault?
不是  现在的重点是帮鲁迪找吸入器
No! Right now we just have to get Rudy his inhaler!
我们要怎么下去
How are we gonna get down?
那树是我们的梯子啊
That tree was our ladder.
我知道那树是梯子
I know that tree was our ladder!
是我把它放那儿的
I put it there!
我觉得我缓过来了
I think I'm coming around.
我感觉好多了
I think I'm getting better.
不对  更严重了
Nope! Getting worse.
更严重了
Getting worse.
我的天  心肺复苏术
Oh. Oh, boy. Uh, CPR.
我知道怎么做心肺复苏术
I know how to give CPR.
不用了  谢谢
No, thank you.
试试总比什么都不做强吧
Uh, wh-why don't I just try it?
你要是感觉不好  我就马上停下来
And if you hate it, I'll stop.
-不要  -好吧  听你的
- No! - Yeah, okay, you're right.
坚持住
Just hold on.
-我有主意了  -什么主意
- I have an idea. - What?
-祝我好运吧  -你  你要干嘛
- Wish me luck. - Wh-what are you doing?
也许是我今生做过的最有种也是最蠢的事
Maybe the bravest and dumbest thing I've ever done.
这是献给你的  沃伦・菲茨杰拉德
This is for you, Warren Fitzgerald!
还有你  鲁迪
And you, too, Rudy.
谢了
Cool.
老爸
Dad!
太帅了
Whoa! That was amazing!
来自异域的沙石
你好呀  沙沙
Hello, sand.
还记得这双手吗
You remember these hands?
终于摆脱奶子了
We're finally done with boobs!
吉恩  永远别想摆脱奶子
Oh, Gene, you're never done with boobs.
它们无处不在
They're everywhere you look!
山峰  减速带
Mountains, speed bumps...
看  你自己刚刚也做了一对  小哥
Hell, you just made a nice pair yourself, Cool Breeze.
你玷污了沙沙
You've ruined sand!
该死  还是没结果
Darn it. We still haven't settled this.
我真不明白  怎么会有人认为我是呆瓜
I don't get it. Why would anyone think I'm a dork?
那我为什么会被认为是呆瓜
- Well, what makes me a dork? - Well, um,
因为你对蛇颈龙的迷恋  还有你的漫画
you're a dork for plesiosaurs. And your comic book.
漫画小说  不过也对  漫画我也涉猎
Graphic novel. But, yes, I also dabble in comic books,
-也玩人形公仔和贴纸  -对  看吧
- action figures, and stickers. - Yeah. See?
你是呆瓜是因为你对马的迷恋
Well, you're a dork for horses.
马确实是我迷恋的东西  之一
Huh, I am. Among other things.
看来我们各有各的"呆"
Hmm. I guess we're both dorks in our own way.
各位  我有话要说
Everyone! I have an announcement.
想必大家都很想知道蒂娜和亨利
You're probably all wondering how the voting came out
呆瓜争议的投票结果
in the Tina/Henry dork controversy.
不想
No.
结果出来了  我是呆瓜
Well, the verdict is in. I'm a dork.
我迷恋男生  马  和僵尸
For boys and horses and zombies.
我也是呆瓜  迷恋恐龙和连环漫画小说
And I'm a dork for dinosaurs and my series of graphic novels.
那我就是迷恋跳舞的呆瓜咯
I guess I'm a dork for dancing.
我是迷恋沙沙的呆瓜
Okay, then I'm a dork for sand.
我是不是就成了迷恋奶子的呆瓜
Guess that makes me a dork for boobs.
我是迷恋奥利的呆瓜
I'm a dork for Ollie.
我是迷恋安迪的呆瓜
I'm a dork for Andy!
我是迷恋廉价夏敦埃酒的呆瓜
And I'm a dork for bargain Chardonnays
也是喜欢被辅导员小哥搭讪的呆瓜
And being asked out by handsome guidance counselors.
你呢  福旺德老师
What about you, Mr. Frond?
我是喜欢大家都按时上车的呆瓜
I'm a dork for getting on the bus on time.
拿上你们的东西  我们走了
Get your buddies and let's go!
打给我
Call me.
如果是我妈接的就赶紧挂了
If my mother answers, hang up.
也许我们都是不同领域的呆瓜
We might be dorks for different things,
但在我们内心深处  我们都
but at our cores, we're all...
一样  道理讲完了  大家可以走了
the same. I made a very good point. Let's all go now.
男孩来自火星  女孩来自金星
Boys are from Mars, girls are from Venus.
我有屁屁  你有鸡鸡
I've got a yum-yum, you've got a penis.
-琳达  -咋了  咋了
- Uh, Linda? - What? Ow. What?
我们商量过了  想让你离开
Uh, we've been talking, and we want you to leave.
啥  是吗
Wha... Really!
-你们想让我离开  -对
- You want me to leave? - Yeah.
你们用喊的啊
Well, chant for it.
等等  不好意思
Oh, wait. I'm sorry.
对哦  你们不会喊
That's right. You can't chant! Ha!
压几下  我  我看看说明
How many pumps? L-let me read the instructions.
怎么  你难不成是怕他吸太多吗
Oh, what, you're worried he's gonna breathe too well?
-快啊  -好吧
- Come on! - Fine!
谢谢你
Thank you.
兄弟
Buddy.
我恨你
Oh, I hate you.
但我爱空气
But I love air.
看来我是摆脱不了你了
So I guess we're stuck together.
给我吸一口
Let me get a puff of that.
你们不能呆在这里面  怎么回事
Hey! You're not allowed to be in here. What's going on?!
我们...  快跑
Uh, we're, uh... Run!
-我们的要求  -琳达快走
- What do we want? - Linda gone!
-何时实现  -立刻马上
- When do we want it? - Now!
你们休想赶走我
Linda Belcher's here to stay!
反正我也不在这儿工作
I don't work here anyway! Boo!
我的脸
Oh, my face!
工贼[指不参加罢工的人]
Scabs!
工贼来了
Scabs are coming!
去抓住他们
Let's get 'em!
只要给钱他们什么都做
They'll do anything for a dollar!
你是本想来给我们惊喜  结果被罢工团
Did you come to surprise us, but then you got caught up
-忽悠去领口号了吗  -是的
- in the chanting? - Yep.
露易丝让你惹上保安了吗
Did Louise get you in trouble with security?
-是的  那我们家里见  -好
- Yep. See you at home? - Yep.
有两个不见了
Uh-oh. I'm missing two.
来了  这两个
Here they are. Two here.
中号鲁迪  我看你有点喘啊
Oh. Regular-Sized Rudy, I detect a bit of wheeze.
他每两小时要用一次吸入器  不然会死
He needs an inhaler every two hours or he'll die.
对  我  我听说了
Yeah. I-I heard about that.
还你你的马甲
Oh, uh, here's your vest.
你拿它干什么了
What did you do to it?!
我拿到的时候就这样
It was like this when I got it.
吉恩  蒂娜
Gene! Tina!
你们今天过得怎么样
How was your day?
-全是呆瓜  -全是奶子
- Dorky. - Booby.
Dorky和Booby都有"愚蠢"的意思
很好  很好  很高兴你们玩得开心
Great, great, glad you had fun.
-我觉得我们没事了  -我们逃掉了
- I think we're in the clear. - Yeah, we got away with it.
这不是你该从今天的经历中学到的
That's not what you should be taking away from this.
你觉得呢  小鲁
Did we get away with it, Rude?
这坏事做得太爽了
Perfect crime. Mmm.
感受过活的滋味  还想要再体验更多
I've tasted life, and I'm hungry for more.
你知道你差点害死鲁迪吧
You do realize you almost made Rudy die.
差点死掉是人生最棒的部分了
Almost dying is the best part of living.
这就是九死一生的领悟
It's called almost-live-dying.
等你经营餐馆的时候
So, when you run the restaurant,
你会把名字改成"露易丝汉堡店"吗
will you call it Louise's Burgers?
不知道  也许吧  爹地
I don't know. Maybe. Daddy.
男孩来自火星  女孩来自金星
Boys are from Mars, girls are from Venus
我有屁屁  你有鸡鸡
I've got a yum-yum, you've got a penis
男孩来自火星
Boys are from Mars
女孩来自金星
Girls are from Venus
我有屁屁  你有鸡鸡
I've got a yum-yum, you've got a penis
扭胯  抖臀
Shake your hips, wiggle your butt
裤子脱下来  再穿回去
Drop your pants, pick 'em back up